sigmasport.co.uk 2018-09-04

# Privacy and Cookie Policy | Sigma Sports

This privacy policy sets out how SigmaSports.com will store and use information relating to you. SigmaSports.com is a trading name of Sigma Sports Limited.

Whether you are shopping with us or just browsing our website, we want you to know that we are fully committed to protecting your privacy. Once you choose to provide us with any information by which you can be identified, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

If you have questions about how we use your data or what we do to protect your privacy, please don’t hesitate to email us at [dataprotection@sigmasports.com](mailto:dataprotection@sigmasports.com).

For all of our services, the data controller is Sigma Sports Limited.

  * How we use your information
  * Sharing your information
  * Email marketing
  * Reviews
  * Online advertising
  * Strava
  * Cookies
  * Links to third party websites
  * Retaining your information
  * Your rights
  * Countries outside of the European Union
  * Changes to our Privacy Policy

## How we use your information

When you shop with us, you’ll need to provide consent for us to process your information so that we can fulfil your order. This consent is our legal basis for processing.

**Type of information** | **How we use it**  
---|---  
**Name and contact details** | To deliver your orders  
To send you service information relating to your orders  
At your request, to let you know when an item is back in stock  
To send you marketing emails (only if you've opted-in)  
For fraud prevention  
**Payment details** | To take payment and give refunds where necessary  
For fraud prevention  
  
Once you have placed an order with us, we’ll keep hold of the following information:

**Type of information**

| **How we use it**  
---|---  
**Your purchase history, browsing history and saved items** | To fufil your orders, provide customer service and handle returns  
To find out what you like, and send you relevant marketing emails (only if you've opted-in)  
To deliver you adverts elsewhere online  
**Your contact history with us** | 

To provide you with customer service and support  
  
You also have the option of providing the following further information:

**Type of information**

| **How we use it**  
---|---  
**Your gender, date of birth and interests** | 

To find out what you like, and send you relevant marketing emails (only if you've opted-in)  
  
**Your preferred country** | 

So that we can send you products and offers that are available in your country (only if you've opted-in)  
  
**Survey responses** | 

To help us better understand our customers’ needs and preferences  
  
**Competition entries** | 

To acknowledge receipt of your entry, and notify you of results  
  
**Linked Strava account information** | To allow you to use our website without having to create an account  
To send you relevant emails about Sigma Sports Strava challenges (only if you've opted in)  
  
When you use our website, we will also collect the following information:

**Type of information**

| **How we use it**  
---|---  
**Your device IP address** | To set your default options such as currency and language  
To protect our website from fraud or malicious software  
**The type of device you are using to access our website** | 

To improve your shopping experience by displaying our website in the best way for your device  
  
We will also use most of the above data for our own internal analysis to help us better understand our customer base, and how our customers use our website. We do this to provide you with a better shopping experience.

## Sharing your information

We will never sell, distribute or lease your data to any third party. In order to fulfil orders and provide you and other customers with a highly personal level of service, we do share your data with the following data controllers:

  * Our delivery companies - [Royal Mail](https://www.royalmail.com/privacy-policy), [DPD](http://www.dpd.co.uk/privacy_policy.jsp), [TNT](https://www.tnt.com/express/en_gb/site/privacy-policy.html) and [DHL](https://www.logistics.dhl/gb-en/home/footer/privacy-notice.html)
  * [DataCash](https://www.mastercard.us/en-us/about-mastercard/what-we-do/privacy.html), our payment service provider, who are a division of [Mastercard](https://www.mastercard.us/en-us/about-mastercard/what-we-do/privacy.html)
  * [Global-e](https://www.global-e.com/privacy/), who we use to process international orders
  * [Trustpilot](https://uk.legal.trustpilot.com/end-user-privacy-terms), who we use to collect customer service reviews (see below)
  * [Bazaarvoice](http://www.bazaarvoice.com/privacy-policy/), who we use to collect product reviews (see below)
  * [Strava](https://www.strava.com/legal/privacy), for account linking
  * [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy), [Instagram](https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388) and [Google Display Network](https://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/privacy/) for targeted advertising
  * [V12 Retail Finance](https://www.v12retailfinance.com/privacy-policy), who we use to offer our customers finance payment plans
  * Brands we stock who offer warranty on their products (in the event that you need to claim on the warranty)
  * Companies who administer the [Cycle to Work Scheme](https://www.sigmasports.com/cycle-to-work-scheme), allowing you to save on the costs of a bike by purchasing it through your employer
  * Marketing and advertising agencies who we work with to run our business

## Email marketing

If you opt-in to receive marketing emails from us, we’ll send you a few emails each week keeping you up-to-date with news of our latest products, offers and in-store events.

In order to receive emails from us, you only need to provide us with your email address. To help you get the most out of our emails, you have the option of telling us a bit more about yourself. By letting us know things like your age, gender and interests, we are able to send you more relevant email content. You are not obliged to do this, and you can update your preferences within your customer account at any time.

If you’ve bought from us, we may use this information to send you emails about similar products that may be of interest to you. Some emails that we send will be based on actions that you take on our website, for example buying or viewing a specific product. We do this to enhance your shopping experience, and to help you find products which we think may be useful to you. Rest assured that we will never make opting-in a condition of receiving a service from us.

You can opt-out of receiving marketing emails from us at any time by:

  * Clicking the ‘Unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of any of our marketing emails
  * Updating your email preferences within your [customer account](https://www.sigmasports.com/auth/signin?t=/account)
  * Contacting our [customer care team](https://www.sigmasports.com/contact-us)

If you opt-out of receiving marketing emails, you will still receive important order and delivery information by email.

## Reviews

To help provide our customers with a fair and transparent shopping experience, we have partnered with two online review platforms: Trustpilot and Bazaarvoice. Following a purchase, we will securely transfer your email address to these companies who will then use this information only for the purposes of inviting you to leave a review.

Here’s how they work:

### Trustpilot

Within 24 hours of placing your order, you’ll receive an email from us via Trustpilot inviting you to leave a review of your shopping experience. To leave a review you’ll need to create an account on Trustpilot. To edit or remove a review you have written, you will need to contact Trustpilot directly.

You can access Trustpilot’s privacy policy [here](https://uk.legal.trustpilot.com/end-user-privacy-terms).

### Bazaarvoice

Around 2 weeks after receiving your product, we may send you an email inviting you to review and rate the product that you purchased.

Once submitted, it usually takes 72 hours for your review, question or answer to appear on the website providing it adheres to our publishing guidelines. Your review can be submitted anonymously or if you prefer you can leave a ratings only review. To edit or remove a review you have written, please [contact us](https://www.sigmasports.com/contact-us).

You can access Bazaarvoice's privacy policy [here](http://www.bazaarvoice.com/privacy-policy/).

## Online advertising

Like many other online retailers, we use a range of digital advertising networks and technologies to send our customers targeted adverts on other websites. The adverts you see will be based on information that we hold about you, for example:

  * Your purchase history
  * Products you have viewed
  * Your interests, as set by you

By visiting our website and consenting to our use of cookies (see below), or by shopping with us and consenting to our terms and conditions and privacy policy, you are agreeing to be served browsing-based advertising.

## Strava

If you choose to link your Strava account with your Sigma Sports account, we will collect the following information from your Strava profile:

  * Email address
  * Workout type (ride)
  * Number of rides
  * Distance
  * Moving time
  * Elapsed time
  * Elevation gain

If you have opted in to receive marketing emails from us, we may use this information to send you relevant offers based on your Strava activity.

You can unlink your Strava account via this page within your Sigma Sports account.

## Cookies

A cookie is a small text file which asks permission to be downloaded onto your computer or smartphone when you visit a website. It allows the website to recognise your device each time you access the website, and will store some information about your preferences or past actions.

We use cookies to improve your shopping experience by doing things like:

  * Keeping your chosen products in your basket
  * Remembering products that you’ve saved to your wish list
  * Sending you email reminders about products you’ve viewed or left behind (only if you’ve opted-in to receive email marketing from us)
  * Analysing web page traffic to make sure that you and other customers can find what you’re looking for easily

When you first land on our website, we’ll show you a message to let you know that we use cookies, and to ask for your consent to store them on your device. You can disable cookies within your internet browser settings.

## Links to third party websites

We may occasionally provide links to third party websites to help you find other relevant information. Please be aware that any such site will not be governed by this privacy policy, and we therefore cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst using it. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the web site in question.

## Retaining your information

We will keep your personal information for as long as you have a customer account with us. This helps us to provide you with a fast, efficient service, from checkout to delivery, each and every time you shop with us.

We encourage you to keep your information up-to-date, and you can do this easily at any time within your customer account, or by [contacting us](https://www.sigmasports.com/contact-us).

## Your rights

When it comes to your personal information, you have the following rights:

  * The right to be informed about how we use your information
  * The right to access any information we hold about you
  * The right to correct any inaccurate information that we hold about you
  * The right to request that we delete information that we hold about you
  * The right to request that we stop processing your information i.e. using it for any or all of the purposes set out in this privacy policy
  * The right to access your information in such a way so that it can easily be transferred from environment to another in a safe and secure way
  * The right to object to, and opt-out of our email marketing at any time

We will always ensure that our services are made available to you in a way that makes it easy for you to exercise any of these rights, at any time. If you have any questions or wish to exercise your rights, please [contact us](https://www.sigmasports.com/contact-us).

## Countries outside of the European Union

In order to fulfil international orders, some data will be passed on to companies within our delivery network who operate outside of the European Economic Area. As with all of our data transfer, this is carried out in a secure way and only the information needed to fulfil your order (e.g. name, contact details, postal address) will be provided.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may update our privacy policy to reflect changes in the way we provide our services to you, or in accordance with changes in data protection law. We encourage you to stay familiar with our privacy policy, but rest assured that If any significant changes are made, we will let you know.

If you have any questions about any changes we make, you are entitled to invoke any of your rights as set out above. We also encourage you to [contact us](https://www.sigmasports.com/contact-us).

## How to contact us

We welcome all feedback, good or bad. If you:

  * Have any questions about how we collect and use your information
  * Would like a copy of the information we hold about you
  * Would like to update or remove any of the information we hold for you
  * Would like to exercise any of your rights explained above

You can either email us at [dataprotection@sigmasports.com](mailto:dataprotection@sigmasports.com), or write to us at:

Data Protection Officer  
Sigma Sports Ltd  
St Johns Place  
37-43 High Street  
Hampton Wick  
Kingston upon Thames  
Surrey  
KT1 4DA  
United Kingdom

This privacy policy was last updated on 21st March 2018.
